Italian Renaissance Painting Photograph Collection: Materials in the Yale University Art Gallery
Yale University Arts Library
Italian Renaissance Painting Photograph Collection: Materials in the Yale University Art Gallery
1900-2005
VRC 23.1
Yale University Arts Library
27
49 boxes
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Italian painting, predominantly from the 13th-16th centuries, which has been transferred to and available at the Yale University Art Gallery. For materials transferred to and available from LSF, please consult the companion finding aid, "Italian Painting Photograph Collection." Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Yale University. Art Gallery
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Italian painting, predominantly from the 13th-16th centuries, which has been transferred to and available at the Yale University Art Gallery. For materials transferred to and available from LSF, please consult the companion finding aid, "Italian Painting Photograph Collection." Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by individual artist name. The individual artist section is further sub-divided primarily by location of work. Preceded by an anonymous grouping arranged chronologically.
Painting, Italian -- 12th century; Painting, Italian -- 13th century; Painting, Italian -- 14th century; Painting, Italian -- 15th century; Painting, Italian -- 16th century; Photographs; Reproductions
- Unknown, Italian-Byzantine, Nativity, YUAG 1871.103 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Italian-Byzantine, St George and the Dragon, YUAG 1871.108 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Italian-Byzantine, Miraculous Apparition of Saints Mercurius and Catherine, YUAG 1871,112 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Betrayal of Christ, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown, Sacrifice of Abraham, Assisi (Box 1)
- Issac Master, Jacob Pretends to be Esau before Issac, Assisi (b/w) (Box 1)
- Issac Master, Ascension, Assisi (Box 1)
- Issac Master, Mourning over Christ, Assisi (Box 1)
- Issac Master, Jacob Pretends to be Esau before Issac, Assisi (color) (Box 1)
- Issac Master, Esau bearing the dish of lentils to Isaac, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown, Funeral of Saint Clara, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown, Construction of Arc, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown (Toretti?), The Building of the Arc, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown (Toretti?), Sacrifice of Abraham (left); Angels appear before Abraham (right), Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown, Wedding at Cana, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown Betrayal of Christ, Assisi (Box 1)
- Unknown, Marys at the Tomb, Assisi (Box 1)
- Magdalen Master (Box 1)
- Florentine school, 14th century, Michael Fighting the Demon, 1871.23 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Ss. Louis of Toulouse and Clara (L); Ss. Elizabeth of Hungary and Anthony of Padua, YUAG 1943.211 & 1943.210 (Box 1)
- Anonymous, Processional Cross, YUAG 1943.238 (Box 1)
- Anghiari Master, cassone, YUAG 1942.324 (Box 1)
- Anghiari Master, cassone: detail, left side, YUAG 1942.324 (Box 1)
- Anghiari Master, cassone: detail, right side, YUAG 1942.324 (Box 1)
- Anghiari Master, cassone: detail, center, YUAG 1942.324 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Battle at the Gates of Rome, YUAG 1942.324 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Story of the Four Sons, YUAG 1943.218 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Story of the Four Sons, YUAG 1943.218 (Box 1)
- Mariotto di Nardo, Marriage salver (Box 1)
- Unknown, Marriage salver with scenes of love and the hunt, YUAG 1959.15.8 (Box 1)
- Master of the Barberini Panels, The Annunciation (Box 1)
- Master of the Buckingham Palace Madonna, YUAG 1871.31 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Annunciation, YUAG 1872.40 (Box 1)
- In the manner of Sogliani, The Dead Christ, YUAG 1871.80 (Box 1)
- Master of the Apollo and Daphne Legend, Daniel with Two Lions, YUAG 1943.227 (Box 1)
- Florentine School, 15th century, Madonna and Child with Saints, YUAG 1871.22 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Italian-Byzantine, Miraculous Apparition of Ss. Mercurius and Catherine, YUAG 1871.112 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Italian-Byzantine, Annunciation, YUAG 1871.111 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Man of Sorrows, YUAG 1959.15.9 (Box 1)
- Unknown, Ecce Homo, YUAG 1959.15.9 (Box 1)
- Master of the Citta di Castello, St John the Baptist, YUAG 1943.243 (3 photographs) (Box 1)
- Master of the Citta di Castello, St Peter, YUAG 1943.242 (Box 1)
- Master of the Citta di Castello, St Augustine (Box 1)
- Master of the Citta di Castello, Madonna and Child (Box 1)
- Master of the Ovile Madonna, Madonna and Child Enthroned with Two Angels, YUAG 1943.244 (Box 1)
- Master of the Monte Oliveto, Diptych: left panel, Crucifixion, YUAG, 1871.10b (Box 1)
- Master of the Monte Oliveto, Crucifixion and Madonna and Child, YUAG, 1871.10 a & b (Box 1)
- Master of the Monte Oliveto, Madonna and Child, YUAG, 1871.10 a (Box 1)
- Master of the Rinuccini Chapel, Noli me Tangere and The Women at the Tomb (Box 1)
- Master of the Norne Tryptich, Madonna and Child, YUAG (Box 2)
- Master of the Rinuccini Chapel, Virgin Presented in the Temple (Box 2)
- Master of the Saint Cecilia, St. Francis Cycle, Assisi (Box 2)
- Master of the Saint Cecilia, Altarpiece of Saint Catherine (Box 2)
- Byzantine School, Madonna and Child (Box 2)
- Byzantine School, Enthroned Madonna and Child (Box 2)
- Venito-Byzantine, Madonna and Child, YUAG 1871.110 (Box 2)
- Master of the Griggs Crucifixion, The Crucifixion, Sassetta, St. Anthony Tormented by Demons, YUAG 1871.58 (Box 2)
- Master of the Castello Nativity, Portrait of a Lady (3 photographs) (Box 2)
- Unknown, Biblical Scene, drawing, YUAG (Box 2)
- Unknown, Study of Woman's head and head of a child, YUAG, 1956.9.67 (Box 2)
- Unknown, Studies for a Madonna and Child with the Infant Saint John, YUAG 1890.28 (Box 2)
- Venetian School (ca 1570), Venetian Noblemen and Two Women, YUAG 1871.96 (Box 2)
- Venetian Painter, Venetian Noblemen and Two Women, YUAG 1871.96 (Box 2)
- Unknown, Flight into Egypt (drawing), YUAG (Box 2)
- Unknown, A Musical Party (drawing), YUAG (Box 2)
- Amadei, Giuliano, Scenes from the life of a hermit, YUAG 1871.37 (Box 2)
- Genoese School, Portrait of a Military Commander, YUAG 1871.107 (Box 2)
- Florentine School, Fernando Cortez, YUAG,1871.86 (Box 2)
- Florentine School, Amerigo Vespucci, YUAG 1871.86 (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Master of the Assumption of Mary Magdalen, Crucifixion, YUAG 1943.261 (Box 2)
- Bartolo di Fredi, Virgin of the Annunciate, YUAG 1943.247 (Box 2)
- Barrocci, Frederico, (Drawing) Studies of arms, hands, head, YUAG (Box 2)
- Barrocci, Frederico, (Drawing)Study of Kneeling Saint Francis, YUAG, 1975.3 (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Barrocci, Frederico, (Drawing) Head of Boy, YUAG 1976.34 (Box 2)
- Barrocci, Frederico, (Drawing) Head of Girl, YUAG 1973.141 (Box 2)
- Zanguidi, Jacopo, Kneeling St. Francis with Angels, YUAG 1972.92 (Box 2)
- Balducci, Giovanni, A King and His Court experiencing a vision, YUAG, 1974.33 (Box 2)
- Acrimaldo, Giuseppe, Summer, YUAG 1959.69.1 (Box 2)
- Acrimaldo, Giuseppe, Winter, YUAG 1959.69.4 (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, Tournament in the Piazza Santa Croce (detail, right 3rd),YUAG 1871.33 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, Tournament in the Piazza Santa Croce (detail, center), YUAG 1871.33 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, Visit of the Queen of Sheba to Solomon, YUAG 1871.36 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido (detail), YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido (detail, center) YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido (detail, left) YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido (detail, right) YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido, YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, Visit of the Queen of Sheba to Solomon: detail, dog, YUAG 1871.36 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, The Meeting of Solomon and Sheba, YUAG (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, Tournament in the Piazza Santa Croce, YUAG 1871.33 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido, YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, The Journey of the Queen of Sheba, YUAG (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, Tournament in the Piazza Santa Croce, YUAG 1871.33 (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido, YUAG 1871.35 (Box 2)
- Apollonio di Giovanni, History of Aeneas and Dido, YUAG 1871.34 (Box 2)
- Batoni, Pampeo, Sheet of Sketches, YUAG 1965.9.16 (Box 2)
- Bassano (copy after), The Nativity, YUAG 1961.61.23 (Box 2)
- Bartolommeo di Giovanni, Penance of St. Jerome, YUAG 1871.53 (2 photographs) (Box 2)
- Bella, Stefano della, Study of a Standing Soldier, YUAG 1971.87.1 (Box 2)
- Bella, Stefano della, Death on a Horse, YUAG 1972.45 (Box 2)
- Cigoli, Ludovico, Studies for the Resurrection, YUAG 1973.67 (Box 2)
- Cigoli, Ludovico, Studies for the Resurrection, YUAG 1973.67 (recto) (Box 2)
- Cenni di Francesco di ser Cenni, Adoration of the Magi, YUAG 1871.15 (Box 2)
- Cenni di Francesco di ser Cenni, Nativity and Resurrection, YUAG 1871.17 (Box 2)
- Cenni di Francesco di ser Cenni, Nativity and Resurrection, YUAG 1871.17 (before cleaning) (Box 2)
- Cenni di Francesco di ser Cenni, Nativity and Resurrection, YUAG 1871.17 (after cleaning) (Box 2)
- Cambiaso, Luca, Rest on the Flight into Egypt, YUAG 1961.64.12 (Box 2)
- Coroselli, Angelo, The Holy Family, YUAG 1.6.1973 (loan) (Box 2)
- Cantagallini, Remigio, Man Standing, YUAG, 1967.48.2 (Box 2)
- Bronzino, Agnolo, Cosimo do Medici, YUAG 1871.78 (Box 2)
- Bronzino, school of, Piero Strozzi, YUAG 1871.84 (Box 2)
- Bronzino, Agnolo, Cosimo do Medici, YUAG 1871.78 (Box 2)
- Bronzino, school of, Piero Strozzi, YUAG 1871.84 (Box 2)
- Brea, Lucovico, Christ Among the Doctors, YUAG, 1943.263 (Box 2)
- Botticini, Francesco, Penance of St. Jerome, YUAG 1871.44 (Box 2)
- Belloto, Bernardo, The Lock at Dolo, YUAG 1929.5 (2 photographs) (Box 3)
- Benvenuto di Giovanni, Madonna and Child with Saints and Angels, YUAG, 1943.256 (Box 3)
- Benvenuto di Giovanni, Madonna and Child with Angels, YUAG 1871.64 (Box 3)
- Biago d'Antonio da Firenze, Crucifixion, YUAG 1871.51 (Box 3)
- Bissolo, Francesco, Madonna and Child, Saints John the Baptist, Mary Magdalen and Two Donors, YUAG 1871.94 (Box 3)
- Bellini, Giovanni, Madonna and Child, YUAG (Box 3)
- Cimabue (Box 3)
- Sandro Botticelli (Box 4–9)
  - Folder of unmounted photographs (Box 4)
  - General Drawings (Box 4)
  - General Paintings (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Cities (Box 5)
  - Berlin (Box 5)
  - Boston (Box 5)
  - Florence (Box 5-6-7)
  - Frankfurt (Box 7)
  - London (Box 8)
  - Milan (Box 8)
  - New York (Box 8)
  - Philadelphia (Box 8)
  - Rome (Box 8–9)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 9)
- Bernardo Daddi (Box 10)
- Dandini, Cesare, Sophonisba Taking Poison, YUAG 1952.24.1 (Box 11)
- Crivelli, Carlo, Madonna and Child, Lehman Collection, NY (Box 11)
- Lorenzo di Credi, Christ on the Christ, YUAG 1871.54 (Box 11)
- Lorenzo di Credi, Baptism of Christ, YUAG 1871.55 (2 photographs) (Box 11)
- Lorenzo di Credi (follower of), Baptism of Christ, YUAG 1871.55 (Box 11)
- Cozzardelli, Guidoccio, Madonna and Child Enthroned, YUAG 1975.112 (Box 11)
- Cozzardelli, Guidoccio, Madonna and Child Enthroned with Saints Catherine and unidentified female, YUAG 1943.258 (Box 11)
- Cortona, Pietro da, Study of Hands, Uffizi (Box 11)
- Cortona, Piero da, St. Bibiana Refusing to a Adore the Idols, YUAG. 1973.5 (Box 11)
- Duccio (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous Places (Box 11)
  - Florence (Box 11)
  - Maesta (Box 12)
  - London (Box 13)
  - New York (Box 13)
  - Siena (Box 13)
  - School of Duccio (Box 13)
- Dossi, Dosso, Portrait of a Lady, YUAG 1871.98 (2 photographs) (Box 13)
- Erri, Bartolomeo degli, Scenes from the Life of Saint Thomas Aquinas: The Birth of Saint Thomas, YUAG, 1871.41 (Box 13)
- Erri, Bartolomeo degli, Scenes from the Life of Saint Thomas Aquinas: The Birth of Saint Thomas, YUAG, 1871.41 (Box 13)
- Franciabiagio, Ss. Gabriel and Michael, YUAG 1871.76 (Box 13)
- Franco Battista, Portrait of a Lady, YUAG, 1974.32 (Box 13)
- Fra Angelico (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous Cities (Box 14)
  - Antwerp (Box 14)
  - Boston (Box 14)
  - Cortona (Box 14)
  - Florence (Box 15-16-17)
  - London (Box 17)
  - Monte Carlo (Box 17)
  - New York (Box 17)
  - Orvieto (Box 17)
  - Paris (Box 17)
  - Perugia (Box 18)
  - Rome (Box 18)
  - Washington (Box 18)
- Agnolo Gaddi (Box 19)
- Taddeo Gaddi (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Cities (Box 19)
  - Florence (Box 19–20)
- Gentile da Fabriano (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Cities (Box 20)
  - Florence (Box 20–21)
- Niccolò di Pietro Gerini (Box 21)
- Ghezzi, Pier Leone, Fantastic Scene, YUAG 1954.58.5 (Box 21)
- Gherardi, An Italian Landscape, YUAG 1938.389 (Box 21)
- Ghirlandaio, Ridolfo, Lady with a Rabbit, YUAG 1871.72 (5 photographs) (Box 21)
- Ghirlandaio, Ridolfo, Lady with a Rabbit, YUAG 1871.72 (before cleaning) (Box 21)
- Giotto (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous Paintings (Box 22)
  - Assisi (Box 22–23)
  - Florence (Box 23–24)
  - Padua (Box 25-26-27)
  - Rome (Box 27)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 27)
  - School of Giotto (Box 27)
- Romano Guilio, Lamentation, YUAG 1973.1 (Box 28)
- Giovanni di Paolo, Madonna and Child with Saints, YUAG (Box 28)
- Giovanni di Paolo, A Triumph of Love, YUAG 1926.9 (Box 28)
- Girolamo da Cremona, Nativity, YUAG 1871.71 (Box 28)
- Girolamo di Benvenuto, Love Bound by Maidens, YUAG 1871.65 (Box 28)
- Girolamo da Cremona, Nativity, YUAG 1871.71 (color) (Box 28)
- Guercino, St. John the Baptist, Sotheby's sale '86, London (Box 28)
- Guido da Siena, Crucifixion, YUAG 1871.2 (Box 28)
- Grenacci, Francesco, Pieta, YUAG 1871.93 (Box 28)
- Ibi, Sinabaldo, Baptism of Christ, YUAG 1871.93 (2 photographs) (Box 28)
- Jacopo di Cione (Box 28)
- Landi, Neroccio di, Annunciation, YUAG 1871.63 (3 photographs) (Box 28)
- Lippi, Fra Filippo, Madonna with Angels and Saint Catherine, YUAG 1871.43 (Box 28)
- Lorenzo d'Alessandro, Enthroned Madonna and Child with Saints and Angels, YUAG 1937.341 (3 photographs) (Box 28)
- Luca di Tomme, Virgin and Child with Two Saints (slightly cropped), YUAG 1943.245 (Box 28)
- Luca di Tomme, Virgin and Child with Two Saints, YUAG 1943.245 (Box 28)
- Marasco, Antonio, Composition: Landscape, YUAG 1941.554 (Box 28)
- Marchesi da Cotigonola, Girolomo, Saint Sebastian, 1871.91 (Box 28)
- Magnasco, Alessandro, Seascape with Fisherman Pulling Out Nets, YUAG 1945.142 (Box 28)
- Rutilio Manetti (Box 28)
- Maratti, Carlo, Vision of Saint Nicholas of Bari, YUAG 1961.64.48 (Box 28)
- In the manner of Carlo Maratti, Pope Clement IX, YUAG 1871.106 (2 photographs) (Box 28)
- Mariotto di Nardo, Legend of Ss. Cosimo and Damien, YUAG 1871.29 (Box 28)
- Ambrogio Lorenzetti (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Paintings (Box 28)
  - Florence (Box 28)
  - Siena (Box 29)
- Pietro Lorenzetti (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Places (Box 30)
  - Arezzo (Box 30)
  - Assisi (Box 30)
  - Cortona (Box 30)
  - Rome (Box 31)
  - Siena (Box 31)
  - School of Lorenzetti (Box 31)
- Maso di Banco (Box 32)
- Memmi, Lippo (Box 32)
- Lorenzo Monaco (Box 33)
  - Miscellaneous Places (Box 33)
  - Florence (Box 33)
  - London (Box 33)
- Nardo di Cione (Box 33)
- Neri di Bicci (Box 34)
- Orcagna (Box 34)
- Piero di Cosimo, The Return from the Hunt, Met NY (Box 34)
- Piero di Cosimo, Saint John the Baptist, Met NY (Box 34)
- Piero di Cosimo, Hunting scene (detail) Met NY (Box 34)
- Piero di Cosimo, The Return from the Hunt, Met NY (2 photographs) (Box 34)
- Piero di Cosimo, Enthroned Madonna and Child with Saints Jerome and Dominic (after cleaning) YUAG 1871.73 (Box 34)
- Piero di Cosimo, Enthroned Madonna and Child with Saints Jerome and Dominic (detail),YUAG 1871.73 (2 photos) (Box 34)
- Antonio Pollaiuolo (Box 34)
  - Drawing (Box 34)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities (Box 34)
  - Florence (Box 35)
  - London (Box 35)
- Piero Pollaiuolo (Box 35)
- Ponte, Giovanni (Box 35)
- Pontormo (Box 36)
  - Drawings (Box 36)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities (Box 36)
  - Carmignano (Box 37)
  - Florence (Box 37)
  - Paris (Box 37)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities: A-P (Box 37)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities: R-Z (Box 38)
- Raibolini, Francesco, Il Fracia, Gambaro Madonna, YUAG 1959.15.10 (2 photographs) (Box 38)
- Raffaellino da Reggio, Allegorical figure, YUAG 1961.61.32 (Box 38)
- Reni, Guido, Venus, Juno and Minerva with Cupid, YUAG 1871.102 (Box 38)
- Reni, Guido, The Martyrdom of St. Apollonio, Collection of Richard S. Feigen (Box 38)
- Salvator Rosa, Landscape with Figures, YUAG 1957.34.2 (Box 38)
- Salvator Rosa (follower of), By the River, YUAG 1970.866 (Box 38)
- Rossello di Jacopo Franchi, Madonna and Child with Ss. Peter, John the Baptist and two Angels, YUAG 1943.219 (Box 38)
- Sano di Pietro (Box 38)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities (Box 38)
  - New Haven (Box 38)
  - New York (Box 38)
  - Siena (Box 38–39)
- Sassetta (Box 39)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities A-Z (Box 39)
  - London (Box 40)
  - New York (Box 40)
- Segna di Bonaventura (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, Nativity and the Message to the Shepherds, YUAG 1946.314 (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, Actaeon and the Hounds, YUAG 1871.48 (2 photographs) (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, shop of, Noli me Tangere, YUAG 1943.232 (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, Way to Calvery, YUAG 1943.230 (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del (shop of), Agony in the Garden, YUAG 1943.229 (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del (shop of), Resurrection, YUAG 1943.231 (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, Saint Sebastian, YUAG 1871.49 (2 photographs) (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, Creation of Adam and Eve, YUAG 1871.49 (Box 40)
- Sellaio, Jacopo del, Madonna Seated on Clouds, YUAG 1871.46 (Box 40)
- Luca Signorelli (Box 41)
  - Assisi (Box 41)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities A-Z (Box 42)
  - Florence (Box 42)
  - London (Box 43)
  - New York (Box 43)
  - Orvieto (Box 43)
  - Paris (Box 43)
  - Rome (Box 43)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 43)
- Simone Martini (Box 44)
  - Paintings: Miscellaneous Cities A-Z (Box 44)
  - Antwerp (Box 44)
  - Naples (Box 44)
  - Orvieto (Box 45)
  - Paris (Box 45)
  - Rome (Box 45)
  - Siena (Box 45)
- Taddeo di Bartolo (Box 46)
- Tiepolo, Muse in a Tondo, Allegory of Poetry, YUAG 1947.17 (3 photographs) (Box 47)
- Tiepolo, Apotheosis of a Saint (Saint Roche between two angels) YUAG 1937.88 (Box 47)
- Titian, Circumcision, detail, YUAG 1871.95 (Box 47)
- Titian, Circumcision, after cleaning, YUAG 1871.95 (Box 47)
- Titian, Circumcision, YUAG 1871.95 (2 photographs) (Box 47)
- Paolo Uccello (Box 47-48-49)
- Francesco Vanni (Box 49)